[
    {
        "question": "Where is the Bankapur Wolf Sanctuary, the first wolf sanctuary in the state, located?",
        "options": [
            "Jharkhand ",
            "Rajasthan ",
            "Karnataka ",
            "Madhya Pradesh "
        ],
        "answer": "Karnataka ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state launched the \u2018Samman Sanjeevani\u2019 app to track benefits under the \u2018Mahila Evam Kishori Samman Yojana\u2019?",
        "options": [
            "Punjab ",
            "Haryana ",
            "Rajasthan ",
            "Uttar Pradesh "
        ],
        "answer": "Haryana ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which city will Reliance Industries build the world\u2019s largest data centre?",
        "options": [
            "Noida ",
            "Ahmedabad ",
            "Jamnagar ",
            "Pune "
        ],
        "answer": "Jamnagar ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country hosted the 1st International Pashmina Festival?",
        "options": [
            "India ",
            "Nepal ",
            "Bhutan ",
            "Sri Lanka "
        ],
        "answer": "Nepal ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state has approved funding for 100 villages under the Forest Right Act for forest management and protection?",
        "options": [
            "Odisha ",
            "Maharashtra ",
            "Chhattisgarh ",
            "Kerala "
        ],
        "answer": "Odisha ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was recently awarded the ECI Media Award?",
        "options": [
            "Sansad TV ",
            "DD National ",
            "All India Radio ",
            "Doordarshan "
        ],
        "answer": "Doordarshan ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which entity has launched a digital knowledge repository \u201cDharohar\u201d?",
        "options": [
            "RBI ",
            "SEBI ",
            "SIDBI ",
            "IRDAI "
        ],
        "answer": "SEBI ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which fintech firm has completed its merger with North East Small Finance Bank?",
        "options": [
            "Paytm ",
            "PolicyBazaar ",
            "Slice ",
            "PhonePe "
        ],
        "answer": "Slice ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has won the men\u2019s singles title of the 120th edition of the Australian Open Tennis Championship 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Jannik Sinner ",
            "Alexander Zeverv ",
            "Rafael Nadal ",
            "Novak Djokovic "
        ],
        "answer": "Jannik Sinner ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Madison Keys, who won the women\u2019s singles title of the 2025 Australian Open Tennis Championship, belongs to which country?",
        "options": [
            "Belarus ",
            "Spain  ",
            "Switzerland  ",
            "United States "
        ],
        "answer": "United States ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which bank became the first in India to adopt Clari5\u2019s NCRP Integration Solution for real-time fraud prevention?",
        "options": [
            "State Bank of India ",
            "HDFC Bank ",
            "ICICI Bank ",
            "Punjab National Bank "
        ],
        "answer": "Punjab National Bank ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Nagoba Jatara is a tribal festival held in which one of the following states?",
        "options": [
            "Karnataka ",
            "Odisha ",
            "Chhattisgarh ",
            "Telangana "
        ],
        "answer": "Telangana ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider the following statements regarding the enhanced Certificate of Origin (eCoO) 2.0 System:  1. It is a platform which provides information about Free Trade Agreement.  2. It is developed by the Directorate General of Foreign Trade.  Which of the statements given above is/are correct?",
        "options": [
            "1 only ",
            "2 only ",
            "Both 1 and 2 ",
            "Neither 1 nor 2 "
        ],
        "answer": "Both 1 and 2 ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Consider the following statements regarding the Wetland Accredited Cities:  1. It is a voluntary scheme which provides cities that value their natural or human-made wetlands to gain international recognition.  2. Under this recently Indore and Udaipur have received this accreditation.  Which of the statements given above is/are correct?",
        "options": [
            "1 only ",
            "2 only ",
            "Both 1 and 2 ",
            "Neither 1 nor 2 "
        ],
        "answer": "Both 1 and 2 ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is theUnified Payments Interface (UPI)  share in digital payments grew 2024?",
        "options": [
            "74% ",
            "83% ",
            "91% ",
            "95% "
        ],
        "answer": "83% ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Reserve Bank of India will purchase government securities worth Rs___ in three tranches and announced several other steps to inject liquidity into the banking system.",
        "options": [
            "\u20b910,000 crore ",
            "\u20b920,000 crore ",
            "\u20b950,000 crore ",
            "\u20b960,000 crore "
        ],
        "answer": "\u20b960,000 crore ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following has taken control of Aviom India Housing Finance due to concerns over governance and payment defaults?",
        "options": [
            "NPCI ",
            "RBI ",
            "SEBI ",
            "SIDBI "
        ],
        "answer": "RBI ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following has received a Certificate of Registration (CoR) from the Reserve Bank of India(RBI) to commence operations?",
        "options": [
            "Signature Global Group ",
            "Alphonic Network Solutions ",
            "Macrotech Developers Ltd ",
            "RMBS Development Company Limited "
        ],
        "answer": "RMBS Development Company Limited ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "JSW Group will invest Rs 2,600 crore to develop and operate two copper mines and establish a copper concentrator plant in which state?",
        "options": [
            "Karnataka  ",
            "Tamil Nadu  ",
            "Telangana  ",
            "Jharkhand  "
        ],
        "answer": "Jharkhand  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which institution will host the first-ever Asia edition of the Global Hyperloop Competition from February 21 to 25, 2025?",
        "options": [
            "IIT Madras  ",
            "IIT Bombay  ",
            "IIT Kanpur  ",
            "IIT Delhi "
        ],
        "answer": "IIT Madras  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was appointed as the Director of ISRO's Liquid Propulsion Systems Centre (LPSC) in January 2025?",
        "options": [
            "in January ",
            "Dr. A.E. Muthunayagam ",
            "Dr. K. Sivan ",
            "Dr. S. Somanath ",
            "M. Mohan "
        ],
        "answer": "Dr. S. Somanath ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who won the inaugural edition of the Women\u2019s Hockey India Leagues 2024-25?",
        "options": [
            "Ranchi Royals ",
            "JSW Soorma Hockey Club ",
            "Odisha Warriors ",
            "Punjab Panthers "
        ],
        "answer": "Odisha Warriors ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which article of the Indian constitution provides for a Uniform Civil Code?",
        "options": [
            "Article 21 ",
            "Article 40 ",
            "Article 44 ",
            "Article 32  "
        ],
        "answer": "Article 44 ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state government has launched the Rythu Bharosa scheme to provide financial assistance of Rs 12,000 per year to eligible state farmers?",
        "options": [
            "Madhya Pradesh  ",
            "Andhra Pradesh  ",
            "Rajasthan  ",
            "Telangana "
        ],
        "answer": "Telangana ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which state government has launched the Chief Ministers Mobile Operation Theater initiative on the occasion of the 76th Republic Day 2025?",
        "options": [
            "Tripura  ",
            "Assam ",
            "Nagaland  ",
            "Meghalaya "
        ],
        "answer": "Nagaland  ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who won the men\u2019s singles title of the UTT 86th Senior National and Inter-State Table Tennis Championships 2024?",
        "options": [
            "Manush Shah ",
            "Payas Jain  ",
            "Harmeet Desai ",
            "Soumyajit Ghosh "
        ],
        "answer": "Manush Shah ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who won the women\u2019s singles title of the UTT 86th Senior National and Inter-State Table Tennis Championships 2024?",
        "options": [
            "Sreeja Akula ",
            "Diya Chitale ",
            "Manika Batra ",
            "Mouma Das "
        ],
        "answer": "Diya Chitale ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the renowned cardiac surgeon who performed India\u2019s first coronary bypass and heart-lung transplant?",
        "options": [
            "Devi Shetty ",
            "K.M. Cherian ",
            "Naresh Trehan ",
            "P. Venugopal "
        ],
        "answer": "K.M. Cherian ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which country has declared 2025 as the \u2018Year of Community\u2019?",
        "options": [
            "Saudi Arabia  ",
            "UAE ",
            "Qatar ",
            "Kuwait "
        ],
        "answer": "UAE ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "\u201cWhen-listed\u201d platform is an initiative of:",
        "options": [
            "Securities and Exchange Board of India ",
            "Reserve Bank of India ",
            "World Bank ",
            "World Economic Forum "
        ],
        "answer": "Securities and Exchange Board of India ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has become the first fintech in India to launch a full-scale Central Bank Digital Currency (CBDC) wallet, e-rupee (e\u20b9), in collaboration with the Reserve Bank of India (RBI) and Yes Bank?",
        "options": [
            "wallet, e-rupee (e\u20b9), in collaboration with the Reserve Bank of India (RBI) and Yes Bank? ",
            "Upstox ",
            "Instamojo ",
            "CRED ",
            "MobiKwik "
        ],
        "answer": "CRED ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who has launched beta version of e\u20b9 wallet, becomes first fintech to integrate RBI\u2019s digital currency?",
        "options": [
            "Upstox ",
            "CRED ",
            "Groww ",
            "MobiKwik "
        ],
        "answer": "CRED ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which rocket of the Indian Space Research Organisation (ISRO) launched the NVS-02 satellite in January 2025?",
        "options": [
            "GSLV F15 ",
            "PSLVC-60 ",
            "PSLVC-61 ",
            "PSLVC-59 "
        ],
        "answer": "GSLV F15 ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Indian cities have been included in the inaugural Wetland City Accreditation list of cities under the Ramsar Convention on Wetlands?",
        "options": [
            "Indore and Udaipur ",
            "Bhopal and Jaipur ",
            "Varanasi and  Mysuru ",
            "Surat and Ahmedabad "
        ],
        "answer": "Indore and Udaipur ",
        "source": "Unknown"
    }
]